Hi, my name is Elizabeth Banks and I
feel blessed. A
>> wow.
>> About being Conan O'Brien.
>> You are a terrific actress.
>> Thank you.
>> You are.
>> That was That took a lot.
>> You might be the best. The absolute
best.
>> You believed it. Everyone believed it.
>> Hey there. Welcome to Conan O'Brien
needs a friend. I'm sitting here with
Sona Obsession. Blessed to be sitting
with you, Sona.
>> Hey, that's nice.
>> Also filling in from Matt Gorly is our
trustee David Hopping.
>> Hello. Also blessed.
>> Also, Oh, yeah. Sure.
>> You're also blessed to be sitting here
with me.
>> I think you're more blessed to be with
me. Um, but anyway, you're hanging on by
a thread. We have something to talk
about today,
>> which is uh Sona apparently, and I have
not talked to her about this yet,
>> but she told me that she had a very
intense
um frackus. It's a word you don't hear
much.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh on the street with somebody and I
want to hear what happened. Tell your
tale, Sona. Tell your tale.
>> Is not a pretty sight. So sometimes,
look, sometimes when I'm walking, Oki, I
have her leash.
>> Slow things down a bit. Okie is your
dog. Pokei is my dog. I'll take her off
the leash for a little bit of the walk.
>> A lot of people do it. Cops have driven
by. Nobody cares.
>> But this one day, I'm walking by this
guy's house and I'm I have my headphones
in and I hear him just like talking to
me. And I turn I take off my headphones
and I turn around, he's filming me and
he's going, "Walking your dog off a
leash is a crime, you cord."
>> And then I not kidding.
>> Wait, don't move past that. He called
you the C-word.
>> He called me the C-word like 45.
>> Not that there's Wait, what?
>> I'm not even kid. It was like this crazy
man. And the thing is like I was shocked
at first when I turned around and then I
turned around and I was just like, "Fuck
you." And then I start screaming at him
and he's yelling at me, calling me the
c-word over and over and over again. And
then at one point and Oki was such a
dick for this.
>> Oh, Oi's still there. I thought he had
left.
>> I thought Oki had left and had got on a
flight or something. She did not like
the vibes. So she starts walking into
the street and it makes me look bad cuz
she's like I'm like
>> Yeah. HE'S LIKE WALKING A DOG IS OFF
THIS LEASH IS A CRIME. YOU SEE where
like he's like foaming at the mouth and
then Oki walks into the street and he
goes look your dog's going to your dog's
going to die and I'm going to help kill
it. Yeah. And he's saying this crazy
crazy stuff to me.
>> Is uh this man's had a break of some
kind. You think? don't know what's going
on. I have no idea. But of course, like
instead of just being like, "Sir, you
need to calm down." I yell back at him
and I'm just calling him the f- word.
I'm saying he's an old pathetic loser.
Like, I'm saying all this awful and
>> cuz you run hot. I've I've been with
you. When Sona sees red, it happens
instantly. And I remember a time, I'm
sure we talked about it years ago, when
you and I were in uh we were in New York
and we were at I think Sarah Baths or
something on the upper west side and we
were with a friend of yours and an old
man across the room shushed us cuz you
were talking a little loudly and you I
saw
>> your pupils disappeared and your eyes
were just all white and you were like,
"Excuse me, excuse me." And he was like,
"Too loud." And you were like, "You
think I'm too loud?" And I'm
just the whole time I'm thinking, "Oh,
this is page six in the post." Cuz I'm
sitting here like an idiot.
>> Yeah.
>> And I was trying to calm you down and
you only get angrier.
>> You went a little crazy, too. So this
guy made the mist. He yelled at the
wrong person.
>> He's matching my crazy and he's like,
The thing is, though, he's filming me.
So he's on the he's on the he's in front
of his door. I'm on the sidewalk. We're
just standing here like they're yelling
at each other back and forth and then uh
I'm I'm just like, "Oh my god, where is
this going? Like where's this film
going? And is it is it am I going to get
cancelled for being agist?" So I'm just
like at one point I switch and I'm just
like why are you being so rude? And then
I
Oh, you decided to clean it up a little
bit.
This is after This is after you've
already bitten him in the leg.
>> I have I said some awful stuff and then
at one point he kept calling me the
cword and I was like you're lucky I like
that word. I go I've reclaimed it so
you.
>> I want to see this video somewhere. No,
we have to see the video.
>> I googled it just in case.
>> No, it's not.
>> How do we find the video? Well, you
think this guy knows how to post a
video?
>> I don't. He probably posted it on like
Next Door if he posted it anywhere. But
also, it won't make him look bad.
>> Maybe he doesn't know. Maybe he thinks
he buried the phone and said a prayer
and he thinks that's how it goes out.
Like he might not know. Some people
>> I don't know.
>> I wouldn't know how to post a video.
>> Yes, you would. You'd have people do it
for you.
>> Yeah, I know. When he I mean, yeah, at
this point I have David take me to the
bathroom.
>> I'm going to find the guy and I'll post
the video for him.
>> Oh my god. Oh my god.
>> That would be a great video to see. But
it is upsetting that he called you that.
Yeah, he he called me it. I I've never
heard that word come out of a man's
mouth that many times. So, he's so
angrily. And then at one point, I was
walking Oki and he went back inside and
then I just see him pop out of the back
of his house and he starts filming me
again. And it was it got cartoonish at
this point.
>> Maybe he had a crush on you.
>> I mean, maybe he wanted this. I don't
know.
>> That is how I used to act towards women
I really liked.
>> Oh, no.
>> Yeah. I would wait and I would film them
and I would shout the C-word. And you
know what? It didn't work until it did.
>> Liza said, "I love this man."
>> A
>> he speaks with He speaks his mind. Um,
that's intense.
>> It was intense.
>> So, how far away do you live from this
guy?
>> I He's like around the block from me.
>> So, what are we going to do?
>> So, here's then what happened. I went
home and I told Tac what happened and
Tac got really upset.
>> Sure.
>> And T's like old school. You can't you
can't say stuff like that to my wife.
And so, I was like, "Let's sleep on it.
I bet it's funny tomorrow." And it was.
>> So you both gummied up.
>> So we both gummy up.
>> He can't talk to my wife that way. Let's
take a gummy and do
tropical fruit.
>> Snore. Snore. Snore. Snore. Ah. Hey,
where were we? Oh yeah, that guy. Let's
get him.
>> So then the next day, you know, we're at
home. We drop the boys off at school. We
we come back home and I'm just like
doing stuff and I didn't hear from Tac
for a minute and then I heard the door
open and he came back and he's like, "I
talked to the guy."
>> Oh wow.
>> And I'm like, "What do you mean you
talked to him?" And he just knocked on
his door. The guy opened the door. And
Tac was like, "If you ever talk to my
wife like that or threaten my dog, I'll
have you arrested for assault." And then
he walked away and then the guy started
being like, "Fuck you. you." You
know, just like crazy yelling back at
him. And then he was I think he went to
go get his camera and then went out and
started filming that walk away.
>> Well, it sounds like he got the message.
>> Had you guys had either of you seen this
man before?
>> I never saw him before. I never saw him
before, but he really uh we're not going
to walk by his house anymore.
>> You know, I'm going to say something and
this just occurred to me because we this
is the time that we live in. Going up
and knocking on someone's door like
that. I know
>> that because we live in this era where
someone can shoot you through the door
and say I was standing my ground.
Whatever.
>> I don't know. I I don't know that I I
respect what Tac was doing. He was
standing up for you. I have mad respect
for Tac, but that I don't know if you
should be doing that.
>> I told him not to. I told him I I said
that exact thing. I was like, "What if
he shoots you through the door?" And he
goes, "Well, then that's murder, right?"
And I'm like, "Yeah, but you'll be
dead." I showed him
>> tax up in heaven. I showed you.
>> Oh, wait a minute.
>> I know. I think I was just eating him up
inside. And also, I I don't I think that
guy's all talk. I bet if I walked up to
him, he'd be scared.
>> You know what I think? I think you
should assume he's all talk and keep
harassing him at his doorway.
>> Yeah, I think
>> that's just my advice as a friend.
>> Going to be a Netflix documentary.
>> Oh, put on masks and tease him at night
right at his
>> doorstep. I mean, you know, my petty
side kicked in and I was just like,
should I just take Oi's poop and spread
it all over his lawn and the front door?
Should I egg his house like I used to
egg houses and back when I was in high
school? But then I slept on it. And then
the older mother version of me kicked in
and was like, you know what? Let's let
this lie.
>> She sent her kids.
>> Let's stay away from this guy and if
anyone harasses him, it should be me.
Uh, and it should be done in a way that
we can monetize for the show.
>> Okay. clicks.
>> Oh, that's nice. Way to like resolve it.
What the
>> Did you make a big noise over there?
Really?
>> I dropped my pen, but we got like He's
got pots and pans over there.
>> He's like the sound effects guy on a
drive time show bang bang bang some my
podcast goulash. No, I was going to say
we could Scooby-Doo it and make him
think his house is haunted.
>> Um I think
>> go in it.
>> No, no. I'm just saying what you're
saying dress up in masks and stuff. Give
engineer a way for you to be shot
through the door.
Then we've got something. It's just
something to think about.
All right, we got to move on here.
>> I I have so many good ideas today. My
guest today is an actress, producer, and
director you know from such films as Wet
Hot American Summer, Pitch Perfect, and
The Hunger Games. Now you can see her in
the new Peacock series, The Miniature
Wife. I just adore her. I love it when
she comes by. Elizabeth Banks, welcome.
This is one of those ones where the fact
that uh the guest has to say anything
about being my friend is ridiculous
because we are really good friends.
>> I know. I love it.
>> And um one of the great discoveries
was that uh you and your uh super cool
uh husband are just such nice people and
fun to hang with. and we've hung out in
a bunch of different situations and had
a blast.
>> Yeah,
>> we have a blast. I know. It always feels
I always feel weird whenever I do
someone's
>> podcast where I know like where we have
like a actual relationship.
>> Yeah.
>> That this becomes like a weird like
performance of our relationship. Do you
know what you
>> We're just going to perform being
friends.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I know we've hung out great
>> on a ski mountain for days on end.
>> Uh, and I convinced you to order those
mashed potatoes and that milk bread that
time.
>> Our kids have thrown rocks at each other
and we've intervened.
>> Uh, your kid broke my TV once, as I
recall.
>> I think he did.
>> Yeah, he did. Yeah. My son always into
tech and likes to take things apart but
then not put them back together again.
>> He was like, I got it. I got And then we
came down the remote control. We were
like, he we'd have no idea how to turn
our TV on ever again.
>> Yeah. Well,
>> no. Just try to bill me. Try to build
me.
>> Um, there's a lot to talk about. I
really I'm very excited about this new
project of yours, which we will talk
about, The Miniature Wife, because it
looks fantastic.
>> It's a fun It's fun. It's absurd.
>> Opposite one of I mean, you're one of my
favorites. And then you're opposite one
of my favorite people who I I don't
think I've met,
>> Matthew McFatian. Yeah.
>> Yeah. He's He doesn't want to meet you.
>> Damn it.
>> You know what? I sense this. I've been
in an airport lounge with him and he has
left the airport lounge and cancelled
and canceled his flight.
>> Wow. Wow.
>> He is so He's a delight.
>> He is so good in everything. And so the
idea of you two together and this seems
like a really funny idea. Uh I
absolutely love.
>> Yeah. This the miniature wife. See, this
is me now. I have to like tell you what
it is, right? The miniature is that what
I'm supposed to do? The Miniature Wife
is uh premiering on Peacock um in April.
And yeah, it's this really fun,
absurdist comedy about a couple who have
a lot of relationship issues and are
working through them, but then uh he
accidentally shrinks her to 6 in tall
and she becomes his miniature wife.
>> I like how you add you just toss that
in.
>> Yeah. Like everyone does that.
>> Yeah. And you see where this is going.
>> Yeah. Right. Exactly. She's shrunk to 6
in. But uh it looks really funny and uh
so I am excited about that.
>> Thank you.
>> And uh just also excited to have you on.
We have a lot in common. We're both
Massachusetts people.
>> I still have my Patriots nails on from
the Super Bowl.
>> Yeah,
>> I did my nails for the Super Bowl and
then I kept them because, you know, we
have the red, white, and blue colors for
the Olympics. Um and all of that.
>> And you're also a patriot. Great. I am.
I'm very patriotic. I just wear red,
white, and blue nails at all times.
>> I had my nails painted for Ken Burns's
Revolutionary War documentary. So, we
all have our different reasons.
>> How good is that documentary?
>> It was fantastic.
>> It's unbelievable.
>> Let's talk about that instead. Um, I
like the part where George Washington is
shrunk down to 6 in.
>> Yeah. Uh, no one's coming. you're from
Massachusetts and but you're from a part
of Massachusetts that might as well be
um you know Oz to me because I grew up
right outside Boston in Brooklyn and you
could practically roll out of bed and
and and step into Boston. Um you're in
Pittsfield. I don't think I've been in
Pittsfield in my life.
>> That's you and many many many people. Um
>> it's way out there. It's
>> Yeah, it's in Western Mass. It's on the
border of New York. So we were sort of
like a suburb of Albany. And in fact, I
grew up in what we call in Massachusetts
a divided house, a Yankees Red Sox
house.
>> Oh, I've heard of those.
>> Yeah. So my dad's radio growing up, his
whole life, the news that they got was
out of Albany, New York. So it was a lot
of Yankees. And my mom who's from Boston
proper, Red Sox family. So grew up very
much like we would go um it's I sort of
live equidistant between New York City
and Boston. So, we'd go down to Yankee
Stadium and we would go to Fenway and
every year we still have that tradition.
I took my dad last summer. We'll go
again this summer. Like, it's still our
tradition to watch the Yankees and Red
Sox.
>> Okay. I'm a I'm a good deal older than
you, but I don't know if this was your
your experience growing up cuz things
may have changed. The Red Sox uh Yankee
rivalry became more gental at some
point. I also think baseball in general
because teams switch up their rosters
practically every year. I come from the
era where, you know, the Red Sox team
stayed the Red Sox team and changed very
little for years and years on end
>> and it wasn't a rivalry with the
Yankees. We hated them and everyone in
Boston hated them and they hated us
>> and there were fights uh I mean between
players and there were brawls and it was
this vitrial and late now I it feels
like it all got more gentile. But do you
know what I'm talking about or
>> do I I absolutely agree with that
actually and I don't know how that
happened. When did that happen? It's
interesting. Yeah. I remember the big
Poppy years, the Damon and all those
years were like Yeah, you you Well,
because also was the rivalry was we
would get so close. I remember I watched
um I watched them win the Red Sox win uh
against the Yankees going to the World
Series in a in a hotel bed like crying
like you know like finally.
>> Yeah. I know when they finally won the
World Series I had the same thing. I was
crying and calling my brothers and we
were all emotional and I mean crying for
us means slightly moist
>> which could have been pollen by the way.
>> That's the Irish way. That's the Irish
way.
>> So you grow up in Pittsfield and then
it's like it's also rural. So I picture
you like running around with unicorns.
>> We did unicorns is interesting. Do you
know how many people think unicorns are
real? Unicorns and dragons. Real. I love
that.
>> Really? I didn't know that.
>> That's like our shared myth. I'm
fascinated by humanity's shared
mythologies and that's one of them is
unicorns and dragons, right? Because
dragons were in every culture and they
never existed as far as we can tell. And
so you're sort of like what were people
all over the world in different cultures
imagining the flying lizard thing was
>> I'm okay
>> and we all agree that it just it's like
in all of our literature.
>> I will believe in a in a in a dragon
long before I will believe in a unicorn.
And I'm just saying this to anyone out
there that thinks there's a unicorn.
There is no unicorn. There never has
been a unicorn.
>> I had a friend from Australia who 100%
believed unicorns were real. As an adult
woman, I had to be like, I they're not.
I don't know how to break it to you. And
I felt terrible.
>> There's a medication for that.
I didn't grow up with unicorns, but I
did c I did go cow tipping
>> and I had one of those um
>> very like John Husian
uh high school experiences, you know.
Yeah. Running around in the woods and
like like wheeling rolling kegs out
into, you know, a corn field. Um, by the
way, running, you know, hiding in in
cornfields, hiding off the pontoon boat
on the lake where we were all skinny
dipping and like, you know, very classic
>> America. I've never been naked, so I
don't know.
>> I was I was
I imagining you covering your junk with
a washcloth in the shower
>> at all times. Like just doesn't want to
take a peek.
>> Liza Liza once saw me naked and I
shrieked.
>> Oh no.
>> And uh I'm suing her. I I feel violated.
Um, so you know what's funny is you were
a jock. You were really good at
>> sporty. I don't know. Yeah, I was
sporty. Yes, I was.
>> You were a big old jock.
>> Can you imagine?
>> You were a weightlifter and a shot
putter. You had a thick I've seen
pictures of you thick neck. Your neck
just went right into your head.
>> It's called Yeah, it's called bulk.
>> It's called bulk. I had bulk.
But you uh you were a great softball
player, right?
>> I was. I was on the All-Star softball
team and I
>> and that was kind of the track you were
on.
>> Well, I needed money to go to college,
so I definitely thought like I better be
sporty and maybe I'll get like
recruited. So, I don't know. You know,
when you're 13, what do you know?
>> Um and so I was really into it. My dad
loves baseball. That's why we've been
talking about it. It's so funny. And um
>> he was like a coach and he was he was
just really into it. So, it was also
just I'm I'm the oldest and it was sort
of my way of really spending a lot of
time with my dad. Um, and played a lot.
And then I was sliding into third base
at a practice and I spiral fractured
both my tibia and fibula and my my like
foot was hanging like sideways to my
knee like 90° just dangling off there.
And I spent a really long time on
crutches and in a cast. And that fall,
which at the time was the worst thing
that had ever happened to me and was a
dream crusher on every level,
>> um, and separated me from all my friends
and the thing that I like to do, I found
acting because of it, which is crazy.
>> That's interesting because this ties in
with this theory. I try to tell this to
young people. There are so many times
where this giant boulder lands in your
path and you're convinced this is the
end.
>> You did it in your you said that in your
your uh commencement speech.
>> Yeah. You think it's over and then you
you take a different road and you think
well this is and I think I've I swear to
God I've had like seven of those and
then later on you think oh my god look
at the life you've had.
>> Of course it is so hard to see it in the
moment. So that's the thing you got to
go through seeing it in the moment. have
to get all the way through it and then
sort of take that look and you know the
older we get and Lord knows I'm so old
now
>> you're a child I'm looking at a child
right now
>> and you but you get that that
perspective comes more and more and more
and all those all those like really big
feelings you had about these very big
moments in your life they really start
to fade don't they feelings they just
get a little smaller and a little
gentler and you're just so much easier
with all of that and
>> I feel so easy about that time in my
life when in fact it was really really
bad like
>> the Yeah. and and you're you're crushed.
And I think I actually think that is
maybe the
biggest role of being a parent is just
to provide perspective because there's
so much we can't you know initially once
you're past the feed them help them grow
them clothing and shoes once you you
know there's all that stuff but then
there's this whole part uh that you and
I are probably getting into more now
where it's just expl explaining to them
it's not as bad as you think it is. I
know.
>> Literally, that's 99% of the job.
>> It's It's 99% of life.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And them saying,
"Uh, yeah. You're not right. You're an
idiot." Um,
>> we work hard here at the podcast. Just
pretend we do.
>> Really, really hard.
>> Every now and then we need a little mini
break. Yeah. You know, just that that
quick moment where you maybe you step
outside, you look at the horizon, you
think about what life really means, and
then you come back in and you do some
ads.
>> That's a mini break.
>> That's a mini break. Well, guess I got
big news. Big news. There's a new way to
take a proper mini break with Coca-Cola.
Hey.
>> Okay. CocaCola mini cans, got some right
here, are now available as single serves
in convenience stores near you. And
guess what? It's not just Coca-Cola.
Mini can singles are also available
across fan favorite brands. Coke Zero,
Cherry Coke, Fanta, Sprite. Now you can
turn any moment into a mini break, even
ones that probably didn't need one.
>> You know, you can have one in your
office desk drawer. You can have one in
your back pocket when you're taking that
walk through the park.
>> What?
>> Yeah. And you know, if you're wearing
those cargo pants with all the different
pockets
Yeah. You know how good I look in cargo
pants?
>> Yeah. You're a cargo pant guy. It's just
the right size.
>> Yeah.
>> Coca-Cola Minican, Big Deal, now
available on the go. Malcolm in the
Middle is back. Brian Cranston, Frankie
Munz, Jane Casmmer, and the rest of the
family returned for a four-part revival
event on Hulu and Hulu on Disney Plus.
Turns out Malcolm's been hiding from his
family for years, but Hal and Lois are
determined to get him to their 40th
wedding anniversary party. And as we all
know, there is no escaping family.
Stream Malcolm in the middle. Life's
still unfair starting April 10th on Hulu
and Hulu on Disney Plus. Hulu on Disney
Plus requires bundle subscription terms
apply.
>> I think I it's it's so being a parent in
of teenagers, which is me now, is
it's uh it's so handsoff on in on so
many levels. And then also like you I'm
really watching how and being reminded
how hard it is to be a human. Like it's
just so hard to be a human and function
properly and take care of yourself and
other people in any decent way.
>> And we have so little leadership to
point to at this moment in time. And so
you're sort of like right teaching them
how to be a decent like it's just it's
impossible.
>> Yeah.
>> It's impossible watching them.
>> I was so proud once of the fact that
I've calmed down. I have more
perspective.
Um I'm slower to freak out. And I was
really giving myself a pat on the back
and I was talking to um my mother-in-law
about it and she's you know she was a
very smart woman and and she had you
know trained as a a therapist and uh she
so I was explaining to her yeah I've
really come a long way and I think I see
and she said well yeah well your
testosterone levels have fallen a lot.
>> Exactly.
>> And and I just was explained to her I I
never had a lot of testosterone. Yeah,
>> they've actually gone up. I'm taking a
pill now. But no, it's but she but she
was right. I realized, oh yeah, there's
okay. So much for my zen wisdom
>> that middle age really, you know,
remember we're we're like two
generations away from people who only
live to 50, right? So like once you're
past that,
>> you're in some evolutionary place that
humans have never really been in. Yeah.
>> And it is so true. I was, you know, I
was talking I had a girls week in Utah
recently. So, my favorite thing.
>> And did you think you would be?
>> Yeah. I like to be invited to a girls
week. I blend right in.
>> He does.
>> We'll get a Manny Petty. And
>> we had Yeah, we did. We did have
massages. Um, but just talking about how
little we give a about so many
things that used to really get in our
craw and now we're just like I think
it's just we don't you literally lose
the hormones that make you care enough
to like mate and and do child rearing
>> and so and now I don't have any of
those.
>> Right. Right.
>> I'm like I don't really I mean do
whatever you want. I'll do whatever I
want. Does that seem like a good plan
for the next 50 god darn years?
Like really, we're gonna keep this
going?
>> Because my body is saying, "Nope, it's
over."
>> Well, this is what you have to look
forward to, kids.
>> If you're in your 20s listening to this,
that's what's coming for you. You know
what I love? detail about you which
makes total sense now is that growing up
and you get into acting and the person
your role model you know I was thinking
who would who would Elizabeth Bank's
role model be as as an actor who would
she want to grow up to be and and it
makes total sense but yours was Harrison
Ford
>> I love Harrison I wanted to be all of I
well first of all when people ask me you
know you were I I was a real go-getter I
was a straight grade A student, you
know, I'm like a hard worker like you.
And so really, it is a work ethic thing.
I just believe you get up every day and
you got to do something with your time
and might as well like, you know, get an
A in math and whatever. I don't know.
>> And so I've just always like had this
work ethic, like this like engine inside
me. And um
>> someone was asking me about like h how
that fed into everything else I ever
did.
>> And I was like, I was competitive with
boys.
It's like I and it's I think it's
because the world was not made for girls
>> and when I looked around I was told you
can be anything you want to be and
everywhere that I looked the boys were
getting to do that. So I was like just
really competitive with boys my whole
life.
>> And so when people asked me like who did
you want to be as an actor? I'm like I
wanted to be Indiana Jones and and I
wanted to be Han Solo and I wanted to go
on adventures and I wanted to have these
incredible like big I that's what I
wanted and the damsel in distress was
not interesting to me and like you know
I I think it really just comes down to
>> I'm I came into this like raring to go
and wanting I want my piece.
>> Yeah.
>> And if you're a woman you're the the men
get all the pieces. So it's like I don't
know. It's always it did not occur to me
to not have my role model be a Harrison
Ford.
>> Yeah. I mean and also when I look at
your career,
yes, you um have had this great on
camera career, but you really quickly
was like, I'm going to be producing. I'm
going to be writing. I want to be
directing. I'm imagine that was not an
easy thing for you to break into.
>> Um no, it wasn't. I mean, it took a lot
of planning and hard work. It definitely
wasn't just luck. It was something that
I was ambitious about and wanted to do.
And of course, you have to be in the
right place at the right time and all
those things have to line up and you
have to find the things, you know, it's
I think my last movie was the movie that
speaks to this point the most though,
right? Like I feel like I was starting
to get like, well, she makes movies with
like a lot of women in them. And I was
like, well, then I'm going to make
Cocaine Bear.
>> Yeah. So good.
>> And I maintain maintain uh maybe there's
like one of the three best movie titles
of all time.
>> Oh my god.
>> When I heard that first of all, I'd be
up for anything that you were involved
in. But when I heard that it was Cocaine
Bear,
>> I was obs I I became a cocaine.
>> Don't even watch it. You don't need a
trailer. You just want
>> You need a trailer.
>> No, we said that. We were like, it's
like snakes on a plane. You know exactly
what it's going to be, guys. There's
going to be a bear. It's on cocaine. Um,
I only say that to say I I don't like I
I don't I like surprising people. I
don't like being put in a box. I feel
like I still have a lot to offer and
nothing's gone the way I thought it was
going to.
>> Yeah. Well, nothing ever does.
>> Nothing ever does.
>> It's a It's a kooky football play. This
was the idea and you're going to break
that way and the hole's going to be over
here and then I'm going to throw that
way and then uh hut hike and then bang,
giant blitz. everything goes to and
then the next thing you know you're
running through the stands with the
football
>> and it's illegal but you're still going.
And that's been my experience in show
business and in life in general.
>> I agree.
>> Um and you know but I I love that idea
that you were not having it and you were
this is what I'm going to do. And what's
interesting is, and there's no way to
say this without uh embarrassing you,
but you are uh a very uh beautiful,
you're a very beautiful woman, and I
imagine that people can dismiss,
you know what I mean? It would be easy
for people to say, "Here's this stunning
stunning blonde bombshell."
>> I'm just your type.
>> I appreciate it so much. But like if you
love um if you love Padma Lakshmi like
I'm not for you. Do you know what I
mean? I love you for saying this.
>> I'm just saying
>> but I'm also like come on Conan. I just
look very like much like your life.
>> Okay.
I did I did think I was marrying you to
be honest. I didn't have didn't have
contacts at the time. Uh no. Uh, yes, my
wife is My wife is very beautiful. You
are both very beautiful, but I'm just
saying I didn't know you the first time
I started seeing you and things when I
saw you show up on 30 Rock. Uh, you are
uh quite stunning. And I don't know if
that makes it easier for people to say,
"What do you mean you're going to
produce or what do you mean you're going
to direct?"
>> Yeah. Well, also I was So, yeah, I was
like, look, I'm that blonde actress,
small boobs, and I have a husband that
produces with me. So, it's like, okay,
the actress and her husband are going to
make a movie, and it's like, I get,
yeah, we're going to try our hardest. I
don't know. It did. It was It It
>> I I don't want to say it's easy to
dismiss somebody who's good-looking
because I've had a lot of success being
good-looking. So, I'll take it over the
uh over anything else every day. Um
>> I had a I had a lot of champions. You
have to do the work. That's And so, at
the end of the day,
>> I just put in the work and I didn't
really think about what I look like or
any of that stuff. It was just I I
absolutely have faced a lot of obstacles
for it. I was literally told by a big
producer once, I just don't think men
are going to follow you as a director.
And I was told like women just you just
don't get action movies. Like you're
never gonna be able to do an action
movie. I mean I literally had like
people look me in the eye and say those
things to me.
>> Yeah. So, it's I don't want to dismiss
the obstacles, but I'm I really like
what we were just saying about having a
lot of grace for those moments in time.
Just,
>> you know, they they build you up and you
you move through it and you just do the
work and put your head down and that's
you lead by example. That's all I've
ever tried to do. Well, I would say to
anybody that has played any kind of
party game with Elizabeth, been any
social situation with her,
>> been in any uh seen her out in the
world,
>> um yeah, I would I would put you in
charge of the forces invading a country.
>> I want to know more about the party
game.
>> Oh, don't with her.
>> That's true.
>> I actually just got I got kicked out of
playing Settlers of Katan with some
friends. You guys, I don't know if you
know this nerd game that
It's a game where you um it's kind of
it's an older game now. It's been around
for a hot minute, but
>> essentially you have to negotiate with
people for things like you're trying to
build the longest road and you're trying
to build a civilization. and you're the
settler of this island
>> and so you have to negotiate and I
basically I became such a cutthroat
negotiator like no you will give me that
wheat
>> because you d and I and like where
people were just like it's getting too
intense like you can't
>> you're not allowed to play with these
people. We touched on this last time, so
I won't go into it, but let's just say I
was in a situation where I was playing
this fun party game with kids and
adults,
>> and at one point someone said, uh, you
know, Elizabeth wants to speak, too. And
I went, and your face had become a mess.
>> Oh my god. And you, I don't even think
you were there anymore. And you were
telling me what needed to happen. And
you were 100% right. She was 100% right.
And I was like, and she's like, you
know, PULL YOURSELF TOGETHER, MAN.
HERE'S WHAT we're doing. AND IN THAT
MOMENT,
>> WE'RE TRYING TO WIN.
>> YEAH. WE'RE TRYING TO WIN. PULL YOURSELF
TOGETHER. BUT I JUST, SHE slapped me.
>> But in that moment, I saw like, hey,
Eisenhower did a great job with D-Day.
But had he not been available and we had
a time machine, I'd get
>> Elizabeth Banks, and I think we would
have been in Berlin a year earlier.
>> Oh, yeah. I would have handled that.
>> Yeah. I know.
really really impressive.
>> This entire theme of our conversation so
far is is my intense competitiveness.
I'm feeling it.
>> I mean I but also I don't have any issue
with that. I like people that care. I
like people that do the work, have a
really strong work ethic. And I think
the rule is you need to treat other
people well. Yeah. And sometimes um it
can be tempting if you're if you're
really incredibly determined and psyched
to not treat other people well and you
have to watch yourself all the time or
you can be brusk with people and David
of course you've never seen that happen
once.
>> No.
>> Okay. You're dismissed by the way. Um
>> but um so yeah it's it's a constant
challenge but I I think do the work. Do
the work and and care care about it. It
is funny. I mean, I you're bringing up a
I I've definitely had those moments,
too, though, where as a leader, I'm
like, "Oh, not everybody wants to work a
hundred hours this week." That's just
me. I'm like, "Oh, right."
>> That's it's you do really have to take
care of people that are, you know, I'm
I'm I want to go a million miles a
minute, although less so now. I say that
like every day.
>> But you know what? Here's here's the
thing, cuz I say that all the time.
>> I know. and and Liza and I was saying to
Liza, "Why do people make me?" And she
went, she'll always step in and go, "No
one's making you anything. You had this
idea. You said we're going to build a
giant catapult."
>> Yeah. Exactly.
>> And uh you know, whatever. So, yeah.
Exactly. So, it's my own It's my own.
>> You always will say like, "Hey, let's
try to keep the schedule a little light
next month." And then
>> everything month of my life. And it's
never it never happens. I'm always like,
"Oh, yeah. I saying no. No is a complete
sentence. Here we go." And then I'm
like, "Well, if you can make it work
with the schedule." And then someone's
like, "So, you want to do it?" And I'm
like, "Well, I'd be interested in doing
it. If it works with the schedule, I
think that's a worthwhile thing to to
pursue and do." Okay. So, we're doing
it. Oh, we're doing it. Oh, Okay.
Well, I guess you scheduled it.
>> But then I switch But then I switch into
this. I'm indignant that someone made me
do this.
>> And I'm like, who is it?
>> There's no winning.
>> Who is it, David?
>> Why is this on the schedule that Conan
builds stone wall recording in the woods
in the woods of Maine? And then just
like you wrote me a text that said, I've
agreed to build the stone wall in Maine.
>> Uh, exactly.
>> So, yeah, that's my own doing. I'm
curious um because you talk about this
dynamic uh you know being um being a
woman in this industry uh and also
trying to manage being in a
relationship.
I feel like all of this would be
addressed in this new show a little bit.
>> Ah
>> do you know what I mean? Don't you
think?
>> I love a segue. No, but don't I mean
that's what I was thinking is like this
there's this obviously really cool
looking if because if if if people check
out the show it it's it's a very cool
when you shrink down
>> and you're having these scenes with
Matthew it's a very cool um looking like
funl looking dynamic but then I'm
thinking like this is talking about
something that's probably close to your
heart. I definitely it's based on a
short story and I I when I read the
story, it really is about how you
minimize your partner's feelings and how
women generally are very minimized and
>> um it's it how culturally that happens
but also in relationships like between
in in the power dynamics in a couple and
um
>> I definitely felt like it was a fun
metaphor like a very on-ose metaphor and
then also we get to really play with it
because this character is very
complicated and not a great person.
Neither one of them are particularly
great people and you're kind of like
rooting for them to figure out that
they're the best version of each other
when they're whole and together. Um the
show was really technically challenging.
My my husband Max said that he thought
it was the least mentally prepared I was
for a job ever. And I think he was
right. I just didn't realize how
technical being 6 in tall was. I was on
a green screen half the time. Matthew
and I were separated. I live in a
literal dollhouse, which was great. They
built like a replica of my home that I
live in, but he's in a realsized house
like doing everything. And then they
would make these incredible life-siz
props. So, a remote control that's six
feet tall, bigger than me that I like
can't push, you know, I'm trying to push
buttons and a mini a travel size
toothpaste that's, you know, comes up to
my chest and a giant Chanel lipstick at
one point because still got to look
pretty when you're 6 in tall. I guess
patriarchy.
>> You know, it was really fun. Um my my
co-star becomes um like a doll like a a
action
figure like a a a guy who goes to space
you know um and things like that. So it
was really the technical stuff was
really fun and wild. At one point I jump
off of a toilet onto a plunger and they
built a life-siz
30ft tall plunger that I like wire onto
and slide down and
>> like a toilet plunger.
>> Amazing. I have moments
>> I walked on to set I was like who how
does this I don't know people's brains
are saying hey where's this AI I've been
hearing so much about.
>> Exactly. Uh, but I have so many moments
in my life cuz I went down this crazy
stupid path where I step outside my ba
body and say, "What are you doing?" I'll
be in an absurd situation, an absurd
outfit doing an absurd thing at my age.
>> And you just do it cuz it's the work.
And then you're standing there and
you're stepping outside yourself and you
catch a glimpse of yourself in a
reflection and you go, "What happened?"
Totally. So, you're thinking, "Okay, I
got into this to be Harrison Ford and
I'm jumping off a toilet onto a plunger.
>> It's on a wire on a giant green screen."
And by the way, so vulnerable. I've
never felt this vulnerable either. I
would I I was st I I would stand on this
giant green box 30t in the air. So, I
would get like wired up onto it. I'm in
all this like gear and the whole room is
green except for uh the area where the
crew is. Mhm.
>> And right before action, I would be
like, "Okay, so where am I again?"
Right. So, I'm in I'm outside. It's
snowing. There's a cat chasing after me.
I'm going to jump off this building,
which is just a curb on the street cuz
I'm only 6 in tall. So, I'm pretending
I'm on a curb on a street outside and
it's snowing and there's a cat and
action and like I have to imagine all
that in my brain cuz I'm just seeing
green and like Larry the the grip just
walking over to get pour a coffee at at
the craft service cuz he's not doing
anything. You know what I mean?
>> And so I I I was like what is going on?
you know, and they're all just sitting
in front of me and I I finally I said,
"Guys, I I actually need you to bring in
like some curtains or something. I I
can't right that's too much to ask. That
is too much."
>> Alone in this space trying to imagine
all these things happening to me so I
can take the audience on the journey of
the 6-in tall woman.
>> Yeah.
>> And h watch, you know, everybody like
chit cchatting over the donuts like,
"Can we I need a I need a curtain. I
need a curtain." So every so they
literally just slid a curtain in and put
slid like a 20 buy in and just put every
everybody behind it for me.
>> It is too much to ask when you're in
those situations and someone walks in.
>> Yeah.
>> And you know they're shaving or
something in front of you.
>> Yeah. Um, you know, it's funny because I
was thinking about you've you've done
you've you've had all this um
highprofile success, but probably I'm
going to guess one of the things you
hear about the most is a project that at
the time you thought, okay, that came
and went and no one cared, which is Wet
Hot American Summer. Like that's one of
those projects that had all of its life
later. Is that right?
>> Yeah, it premiered at Sundance in 2001.
It was one of my first films. I actually
had to pick my name to be on that movie
because I'm Elizabeth Mitchell and there
was already an Elizabeth Mitchell and
SAG. Shout out to her. She was lovely.
She was on Lost, one of my favorite
shows forever.
>> And um so I had to change my name to
Banks. And I remember
we were at Sundance. We thought it was
just the greatest thing ever. And then
no one cared. It didn't get did no
business. And then it started showing. I
remember in New York, I want to say like
at Webster Hall or somewhere it started
showing like late like how they used to
do um Oh, sorry. What is that?
>> Rocky Horror Picture Show.
>> Thank you. Rocky Horror Picture Show.
>> Yeah.
>> And so they were they were having these
screens and it was getting like a little
traction and this is back when DVDs have
so then people just had the DVD of it I
guess. And nothing it completely changed
my life. I went to Sundance. I met my
still my manager to this day. 25 years
now it's been. and started going on real
auditions. Some of which in those very
early days I auditioned for uh to be in
Spider-Man and Catch Me If You Can and
that led to Seab Biscuit, which actually
put me on the map in Hollywood. And then
uh years later got an audition for
40-year-old Virgin because all those
guys, Seth and Evan and all those guys
were addicted. You loved it. And I was
in 40 Virgin and suddenly, oh, she's
funny. And then I got 30 Rock. So like
truly and I'm still friends with David
Wayne. I took him on a USO tour a while
back. Great. We literally went all over
the world together, the director, writer
director of it. Yeah. I I still to this
day I'm like that changed my whole I
can't believe I'm part of that insane
ensemble.
>> Yeah. It's there are these movies that I
think right after Fargo, I could be
getting this wrong, but I think after
Fargo, which you know wins they it's an
Academy Award-winning film and it's a
huge deal. Oh, the Cohen brothers, I
think, made Big Labowski and
>> yeah,
>> people were like, "What's this?" And um
this is weird, you know, and it's at the
time even people making it, you know, on
the set were probably thinking, "What is
this? We're making giant bowling pins
and what's happening here? What are we
doing?" And then um you know that's
probably their that's the movie that
people know
>> uh every word to every single word and
it's become this um I don't know this
text that everybody that generations
memorize. Well, I'm going to shout out.
We were we were skiing. Um Conan knows
where I ski. And um we were skiing and
we were getting lunch and this the
waiter brought our lunch out
>> and he was shaking and he had sauce all
over his face and I didn't quite clock
it at first that he was he was basically
like I have barbecue sauce all over my
face
>> and he was doing like an homage to the
barbecue sauce scene in Wad from 25
years ago. this like 22-year-old and he
was so excited
>> that he was talking and like shout out
to this guy cuz he really committed to
the bit.
>> Yeah,
>> it was very impressive. All my friends
were like, "What is happening?"
>> And the minute we got it, he just lit up
with joy like, "Okay, it works." Like,
"She understands what's happening."
>> And then you had such
>> like a dear like when people were like,
"What's the weirdest thing a fan's ever
done?" That's close to the top of the
list. But you know that is um that is
it's one of those gifts that just keeps
giving where
>> you do something you made it. That's a
very discreet time in your life when
you're very young and then uh you know
someone who's
>> wasn't born
not born when that was made is now so
hears that you're out there
>> and needs to do this to connect with
you. And that's the nice thing, too, is
in those moments, you want to be the
person that they want you to be. I know.
You know what I mean?
>> Of course,
>> you don't want to be like, "Hey, you
know, that's not funny. Get that off
your face.
>> Get that."
>> No, I always look at I I get to come and
talk to you and get to do these things
because people watch the things that I
make. Like, period, full stop. If people
didn't care about the stuff that we
made, you and me wouldn't get to be
here. So, I'm constantly like, h, thank
you so much to anybody who cares at all
to watch it. It amazes me constantly.
>> Okay, you've you've made this show. Uh,
and what is the what's the next step for
you? What's going to the future? Are you
really going to try and calm down a
little bit or is that total
>> I'm literally I literally started
>> cuz I'm not I'm not going to calm down.
>> I was in a writer's room yesterday.
Conan,
>> how much do you love a writer's room?
>> I love a writer. Who doesn't love a
writer's room?
>> Well, I think there are people that
don't probably, but I I
>> Oh, I love it.
>> It's the only place I stop them from
doing work.
>> None of us know if Conan's in the office
and then we just hear a bang and a
scream downstairs when he's in the
writer room.
>> I always kick the door open in a
dramatic fashion AND THEY GO, "WHOA!"
>> AND ALL OF US UP HERE START doing a very
over-the-top bit. Um, and
>> are you carrying coffees in or why you
got to kick
>> No, I don't give them anything.
>> Right. That's okay. I was just
confirming giving. It's about taking
>> confused. Yeah.
>> This is where you and I are very
different.
>> I'd have torn that guy with barbecue
sauce on his face a new
>> HOW DARE YOU, SIR? I'M trying to enjoy
my appreci.
>> Um, yeah. Well, this has been an
absolute joy. I uh I love you dearly.
And yes,
>> I love you, too.
>> Um, you look you look a lot like my
wife.
It's not weird.
>> It's not weird at all. And I think Max
gets it, right?
>> He does. He gets it.
>> He gets it. He's And you know what the
nice thing? Not threatened at all by me.
>> No man is
your shot, Conan. Take your shot. Um,
Miniature Wife on Peacock. And um, I've
never met your co-star,
>> Matthew Fattian. I'm going to tell him
to come hang out with you. Well, just
tell him that cuz he also did a show um
about the assassination of Garfield. I
think it's called Death by Lightning. He
plays the assassin Gitio uh Charles Gau.
And
>> I mean that guy can be anything he wants
to be.
>> Well, his American accent is really
good.
>> It's better than my American accent.
Most people don't realize how British he
is.
>> Yeah. I'm kind of obsessed with him. Uh
and so when I heard you two, I'm
obviously I'm obsessed with you. when I
heard you two were making uh something
together and I checked it out and it's
really great and so
>> um congratulations.
>> Thank you.
>> Please come back tomorrow.
>> Yeah,
>> we'll both be busy.
>> apparently
>> we'll start managing your schedule, too.
>> Take it into my schedule.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Someone will I'll reluctantly say yes
and then I'll just be here.
>> I'm judging a potato sack race
>> in uh in Quebec. Uh all right. God bless
you. God bless you. God bless you. When
it comes to snacks, you know what's a
real crowd-pleaser? Don't even try. I'll
tell you.
>> Yeah.
>> Neutra Grain.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> It's made with 10 g of whole grains, 10
vitamins and minerals, no high fructose
corn syrup. That's important.
>> Enjoy classic favorites like strawberry,
apple, cinnamon, and blueberry flavors.
Plus, check out Neutrorain Crunchy. Let
me tell you a little bit about Crunchy.
It's a new satisfying snack option with
fiber, whole grains, and new craveworthy
flavors like chocolate chip chia. Lot of
cha cha cha going on in there. And honey
oat flax. Each crisp, satisfying, and
delicious neutrorain crunchy bar
contains at least 23 gram of whole
grains and provides a good source of
fiber. Okay, gang. What are your
favorite flavors? Sony, you go.
>> I I go with the classic strawberry
flavor. I love it. I could have a
thousand of them.
>> And David,
>> I recently tried the crunchy one. I had
the honey oat flax one and it was
incredible.
>> It's so funny. I heard a crunch and then
I heard you just moaning with pleasure
and I ran in and you were devouring a
crunchy autin crunchy and you seem so
happy.
>> I was find nutritious and always
delicious neutrorain bars at your
favorite store or online retailer today
and look for new neutrorain crunchy bars
and stores near you. Many men don't
recognize mental health challenges until
they've already taken a toll because
struggle doesn't always look like
struggle. Pressures show up in everyday
places at work, home, relationships.
Those pressures build slowly, often
without being noticed. In season 3 of
The Visibility Gap, Dr. Guy Winch and
his guests explore how to spot these
pressures earlier and what it takes for
men not to just open up, but to get the
support they need. This is important
stuff. Listen to the new season of The
Visibility Gap presented by Sigma
Healthcare. Okay, welcome back. Uh we're
going to do a staff review today. These
have been quite popular. It's where I
pull people in
>> from our little team Coco staff and uh
talk to them and we find out all kinds
of amazing things about the wonderful
people that make up my empire.
>> Uh and today we've brought in a young
lad named Shawn Doherty. You're a senior
producer.
>> I'm a senior producer. Yes.
>> And um people have said we bear
resemblance to one another
>> a little bit. Yeah.
>> A little bit. You are tall Irish Irish
fell. You've got a little from Boston.
>> From Boston. Which part of Boston you
from?
>> I'm from Brainree.
>> Okay. Brainree. Near Burlington.
>> Close enough.
>> Uh and um just for
>> Yeah. There you go. You've got a little
uh a little bit of a pompador going.
Tiny. Tiny. Was that Did you have that
going before you made it?
>> I did. I swear. I swear to God I did.
Yeah. So, I did I promise
>> I for the Oscars I was uh shooting this
bit where I'm Aunt Glattis from Weapons
and they had a stunt double
>> uh stand in for me. And you will attest,
David, and so will you, Sona, this stunt
double looked absolutely nothing like
me. And the whole time I'm thinking, why
didn't we bring Shawn Dohy in?
>> I mean, you should have come in.
>> What's that?
>> Can I say we actually used Sean when we
were building the studio as a fill in
for you with lighting, things like that.
and you did test podcasts and his were
much better.
>> He was funnier, he was faster. So, um
anyway, uh you have had kind of a
remarkable rise here. You started out as
an intern. What year?
>> Uh 2018 2019
>> at the show. Where was that?
>> At the end of the TBS show. I was there
the last year on Warner Brothers.
>> Y Okay. And what was that experience
like?
>> It was awesome. Be honest. Ruthie was my
boss.
Ruthie Wyatt from our social uh media
priestess. Fantastic. Um she does a
lovely job and also full of sunshine.
>> Honestly, I'll come in in the worst mood
and she'll it'll just go away. There's
like unicorns sprouting from her head.
It's wonderful. So, you're working at
the show. Did you see terrible behavior?
Did you ever see me do anything awful?
>> Oh my god. No, everyone was so good.
Everyone was amazing. I loved the Horn.
>> I'm sorry. That's boring.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We need the
drama.
>> We're here.
>> Everyone sucks.
>> There you go. There you go. No, we're
trying to expose the rats in our
industry.
>> The take down.
>> So, you worked as an intern first and
then um you've just done so well. Let me
tell the listeners a little bit about
you and I'm going to find a way to
on you. I just haven't found it yet. Um
>> it feels like getting called into the
principal's office right now. This is
like
>> This is the part where the principal
butters you up. You started out really
well in third and fourth grade. I
thought you showed great promise. So,
we'll get to that part down. Yeah.
>> Um, you're now uh have risen to this
point where you're in charge of uh
producing Andy Richtor's podcast here,
Rob Low's podcast.
>> And so you're dealing with those two
monsters.
>> No,
>> you can quietly say no. But uh both of
them both of them scour scourges uh on
the business. Um and so you've done
really well and then I find out it was
in the trades that you sold a
screenplay. Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, um, my question is, when am I
getting a piece of your success?
>> You've been a barnacle on this boat a
long time, Sean. So, is there a part in
this stream play for me?
>> Oh my god. Of course. Anything. Anything
you want. Uh, I mean, it's a high school
comedy, so I don't know if there is a I
hate to say it. You might You might have
aged out of your role.
you. Sean,
>> I'm sorry. I'm sorry. You come in here
and you tell me I'm too old to play a
high school student when no one would
have that take.
>> That is agist.
>> It's a little concerning to just see
like you hovering over the teenagers. I
don't know if that would be
>> I think a lot of people would think that
guy fits right in.
>> Yeah,
>> I'm still prepubescent at my age
somehow. Um
>> preubescent.
I'm so postpubes. I came around to
>> pret.
So, um, there's got to be No, I don't
play a high school student, but there
are adults that work at the high school.
>> Do you think you could be principal
disciplinarian?
>> What are you talking about? What do you
think I'm doing right now? You just said
you felt like I was being called in the
principal's office. If you don't find a
part for me in this movie, I will sue
you into oblivion.
>> I will make up things about you.
>> On what ground are you going to sue him?
>> When you reach my state of the business,
which is quite high, this the level that
I'm at right now, I don't need reasons.
>> I've got judges in my pocket.
>> This a lawsuit. That's it.
an audition. Audition.
>> You kids better cut it out. Now listen
dear, you nerds. There's no way you're
going to win against the jocks. See, cuz
I'm with the jocks and you nerds can
stay up all night and work on your
robot. But there's no way you beat my
jocks. See?
>> What role was that?
>> Very 1980s, 1970s.
>> And then later those nerds did what?
>> Blate. I'm the robot they invented. I've
just beat up the football team. No,
>> I think I like the robot, too.
>> This is a great movie. Oh, don't tell me
yours explores relationships and stuff
that might really happen. That's so
boring. You want robots and you want
headmaster.
>> I think you would be uh amazing at this.
I think I think you've kind of sold it.
Takes place in Massachusetts. So, this
is another point for you.
>> Perfect. I grew up in Massachusetts, not
far from you.
>> True. Yes. So, you're growing up in
Massachusetts. What were you interested
in? What was your what would what did
you aim for in show business and how did
you end up at this up place?
>> How did you wash up on this beach of all
places?
>> I mean, I don't know. I wanted to work
in late night television and then it
died the second I came to Los Angeles.
It was just over. Yeah,
>> it was you that killed it.
>> But then it was unfortunately
>> late night television was thriving right
up until Shawn Dhy showed up with his
cardboard suitcase.
Gosh, I'm here from Brain Tree.
>> Oh no,
>> I'm here to see the big city. Where's
the chowder? There's no chowder here.
Where's the Red Sox? There's no Red Sox
either.
>> Um, I don't know why you deserve all
this abuse, Sean, but you do. Everyone,
Here's the thing that I find
disconcerting. You're beloved. Everybody
universally is like, "Oh my god, Sean.
Sean is such a good guy." They're always
talking to me about you and I don't know
what this is, but when I hear too much
praise about one of my people, I find a
way to try and break that. No.
>> And that's what's happened.
>> You identify a threat from within. I get
it.
>> I could, but for you look like me, but
you're younger. He's better looking.
He's got the leg strength. He He could
go
>> leg
podcast. I'm always checking out leg.
>> When men have too much leg strength, I
want them gone because I know that they
will beat the me. I'm the alpha. And he
he could single white female you pretty
easily.
>> Oh, you could.
>> That is what I'm planning to do. I will
say the first time I ever interacted
with you as a PA, you did say, "We hired
this young man, so if someone tries to
assassinate me, this kid will die
instead." Yeah. At like 20 years old.
That was the first interaction because I
had read that Saddam Hussein, you know
this, right? Saddam Hussein hired all
these other Saddam Hussein to look like
him to and you know so that if someone
went to kill Saddam Hussein there was a
nine out of 10 chance they'd get the
wrong Saddam Hussein and that made me
first of all this is why you were hired
Sean
>> we saw you I turned down so many interns
that day and then this guy
>> so much more prepared
>> okay this guy is exactly my height Sean
is 6'4 he's got the red hair the
pompador he's got my look um and I
thought this is perfect and that's why I
kept sending you out for sandwiches even
even when we didn't need sandwiches. I
wanted you vulnerable public
>> and that way you draw out the people
that want to hurt Conan O'Brien.
>> That's the first thing he got from you.
That's the first conversation that you
guys had with each other.
>> I am a notorious Hollywood celebrity
interaction. Yeah.
>> And it's you will take a bullet for me.
That's
>> and not you won't you won't do it you'll
do it against your will.
>> Not out of loyalty. No, no, it was.
>> And it worked because he was attacked
constantly when he went out. I had him
wear a t-shirt that said, "I am Conan."
He would come into the office with
arrows sticking out of him. Rocks had
been bounced off his head. He'd been
kicked by old women.
>> And you, it was like a sponge that sucks
up all the hate gravy. You know,
>> I love the thought that the people
attacking you are old women.
>> Yeah.
>> And you're so scared of them. You send
out a decoy.
>> Yeah. I sent out a 20 I sent out a
20year-old kid and he just gets beaten.
They're hitting you hitting you with
their purses.
They're throwing old neco wafers at you
>> and yet I stuck around. I said, "Give me
more."
>> So, what's the dream? You've written
this screenplay now. Would you like to
>> with my friend Caroline? Yes. We
co-wrote it. Yeah.
>> Okay. And the don't tell me the whole
idea, but the basic idea is these are
high school students in Massachusetts.
>> And uh and
>> it's an homage to The Apartment, the
Billy Wilder movie.
>> Oh, that's terrific.
>> That's great.
>> We'll leave the title out of this. Uh
but it is that makes it sound classy.
Yeah. And it's it's called The
Boat. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, okay. Well, suddenly I'm I'm
distancing myself distancing myself from
the boat. Uh-huh. Yeah. By the way,
I wrote a Good luck with that. I wrote a
screenplay called The Boat that uh
1987 went nowhere.
Uh but um what happens next?
Theoretically, you've sold it. Is there
a ch How does these things get made? How
does it happen?
>> That's the million-dollar question. I
mean, I don't know.
>> I know. I know very little about the
film business,
>> but you're you're a movie star now, too.
Uh
>> it's true. Yeah. I'm just flooded with
offers.
Uh, no. I uh I honestly don't understand
that business at all. And and
increasingly I don't even understand the
business I was in. It's all changing so
much. But
>> that's very impressive that you sold a
screenplay
>> and you're kicking ass here at the show.
Uh, and people, again, much to my
irritation, think you're a wonderful
person. Uh, and I'm tired of it. I'm
really tired of it. So, we're letting
you go.
>> That is all right. That is This was the
exit interview. I could feel it coming.
>> I had filing a complaint with the
writer's guild.
>> Perfect. Yes.
>> That boat is my title.
>> I had a catamaran when I was in high
school and I called it my boat.
>> And you know why I called it my
boat, David?
>> Why?
>> So I'd get on it and ride around a
little pond and go, "Nobody wants to
me."
>> What a what a twist.
>> What a twist.
>> Oh my.
>> Audience is just so sad watching it.
>> Me going in a sad circle. Charlie Brown,
there was no win. Charlie Brown, nobody
wants to me. And then, well, good
night, Mo.
>> So, that was my screenplay.
>> I think yours is going to be better.
>> Thank you very much. Yeah.
>> Uh, Sean, thank you.
>> I'm honored to have you on the team and
uh hilarious that my first comment to
you was that you will draw my assassin.